{
    "questions" : [
        {
            "questionType" : "multiple_choice",
            "questionText" : "What does SQL stand for?",
            "options" : [
                "Standard Question Language",
                "Structured Query Language",
                "Standard Query Language",
                "Structured Question Language"
            ],
            "correctAnswer" : "Structured Query Language",
            "explanation" : "SQL is an acronym that strands for Structured Query Language."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "true_false",
            "questionText" : "SQL keywords are case sensitive.",
            "options" : ["True", "False"],
            "correctAnswer" : "False",
            "explanation": "SQL keywords are not case sensitive so writing select does the same as SELECT."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "multiple_choice",
            "questionText" : "Which of these is NOT a SQL keyword?",
            "options": [
                "SELECT",
                "CHANGE",
                "DELETE",
                "DROP"
            ],
            "correctAnswer" : "CHANGE",
            "explanation" : "CHANGE is not a valid keyword in SQL."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "text_input",
            "questionText" : "What SQL keyword is used to select data from a database?",
            "correctAnswer" : "SELECT",
            "explanation" : "The SELECT keyword is used to select data from a database."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "fill_blank",
            "questionText" : "Complete the SQL query to select all available fields from 'myTable':",
            "displayText" : "SELECT _ FROM myTable",
            "correctAnswer" : "*",
            "explanation" : "The * symbol can be used with SELECT statements to select all fields."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "fix_error",
            "questionText" : "Fix this SQL query to select the 'Name' and 'Age' columns from 'myTable':",
            "displayText" : "SELECT Name, FROM myTable;",
            "correctAnswer" : "SELECT Name, Age FROM myTable",
            "explanation" : "To SELECT multiple columns from a table, place their names after the SELECT keyword and separate them with commas."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "true_false",
            "questionText" : "A SQL column can contain duplicate values",
            "options" : ["True","False"],
            "correctAnswer" : "True",
            "explanation" : "Duplicate values are allowed in SQL colums."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "multiple_choice",
            "questionText" : "What SQL keyword combination is used to select only different values?",
            "options" : [
                "SELECT DISTINCT",
                "SELECT DIFFERENT",
                "SELECT UNIQUE",
                "SELECT NOT SAME"
            ],
            "correctAnswer" : "SELECT DISTINCT",
            "explanation" : "The DISTINCT keyword can be used with SELECT to only return the different values from a column."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "fill_blank",
            "questionText" : "Complete the SQL query to select only distinct values in the 'Name' column of 'myTable':",
            "displayText" : "SELECT DISTINCT ____ FROM myTable;",
            "correctAnswer" : "SELECT DISTINCT Name FROM myTable",
            "explanation" : "Remember the desired column names should be placed after the SELECT statement (and after modifiers such as DISTINCT)."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "text_input",
            "questionText" : "What SQL keyword is used to extract records that satisfy a certain condition?",
            "correctAnswer" : "WHERE",
            "explanation" : "The WHERE keyword can be used to filter records from columns if they satisfy the specified condition."

        },
        {
            "questionType" : "multiple_choice",
            "questionText" : "Which of the following are not valid operators used in the WHERE Clause?",
            "options" : [
                "==",
                "=",
                ">",
                "<>"
            ],
            "correctAnswer" : "==",
            "explanation" : "Unlike in other popular programming languages, SQL uses '=' as the equivalence conditional operator instead of '=='."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "true_false",
            "questionText" : "In some versions of SQL <> may be written as != as well.",
            "options" : ["True", "False"],
            "correctAnswer" : "True",
            "explanation" : "Typically it is recommended to use <> as it is most popular but most (not all) modern environments accept != as well."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "fix_error",
            "questionText" : "Correct this SQL Query to filter the 'Name' column only where values are the same as 'Dave':",
            "displayText" : "WHERE Name > Dave;",
            "correctAnswer" : "WHERE Name = 'Dave';",
            "explanation" : "The = operator should be used to filter based on the 'equals' condition."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "true_false",
            "questionText" : "The ORDER BY keyword is used to sort records in ascending or descending order.",
            "options": ["True", "False"],
            "correctAnswer" : "True",
            "explanation" : "The ORDER BY keyword is used in SQL to sort by one or more columns in a result set."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "true_false",
            "questionText" : "The ORDER BY keyword sorts records in descending order by default.",
            "options" : ["True","False"],
            "correctAnswer" : "False",
            "explanation" : "ORDER BY sorts records in ascending order by default."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "fill_blank",
            "questionText" : "Complete the following SQL query to order myTable by the Name column (ascending):",
            "displayText" : "SELECT * FROM myTable\nORDER BY ____;",
            "correctAnswer" : "SELECT * FROM myTable\nORDER BY Name;",
            "explanation" : "The column name should be placed after ORDER BY."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "true_false",
            "questionText" : "To order a result set by multiple columns, their names can be listed after ORDER BY (separated by commas).",
            "options" : ["True","False"],
            "correctAnswer" : "True",
            "explanation" : "SQL allows result sets to be ordered by multiple columns. The ordering will follow the sequence of the listed column names."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "multiple_choice",
            "questionText" : "Which of the following SQL queries can be used to delete all records in myTable where 'Age' is greater than 15?",
            "options" : [
                "DELETE Age FROM myTable WHERE Age>15;",
                "DROP RECORDS FROM myTable WHERE Age>15;",
                "DELETE FROM myTable WHERE Age>15;",
                "DROP FROM myTable WHERE Age>15;"
            ],
            "correctAnswer" : "DELETE FROM myTable WHERE Age>15;",
            "explanation" : "The DELETE keyword is placed before FROM (similar to SELECT). The table is specified using FROM and the condition for deletion is specified using WHERE."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "text_input",
            "questionText" : "What SQL statement is used to group rows that have the same values into 'summary' rows?",
            "correctAnswer" : "GROUP BY",
            "explanation" : "The GROUP BY statement gruops rows with same values into 'summary' rows."
        },
        {
            "questionType" : "multiple_choice",
            "questionText" : "Which of the following is not an example of an aggregate function that can be used with GROUP BY statements?",
            "options" : [
                "COUNT()",
                "MAX()",
                "MED()",
                "SUM()"
            ],
            "correctAnswer" : "MED()",
            "explanation" : "MED() is not a valid SQL aggregate function but MAX() and MIN() are."
        }
    ]
}